<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gitea Actions on 小惡魔 - AppleBOY</title><link>https://blog.wu-boy.com/categories/gitea-actions/</link><description>Recent content in Gitea Actions on 小惡魔 - AppleBOY</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>appleboy.tw@gmail.com (Appleboy)</managingEditor><webMaster>appleboy.tw@gmail.com (Appleboy)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:41:55 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.wu-boy.com/categories/gitea-actions/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Our Team Migrated from Bitbucket Data Center to Gitea Enterprise</title><link>https://blog.wu-boy.com/2026/02/why-we-migrated-from-bitbucket-dc-to-gitea-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:41:55 +0800</pubDate><author>appleboy.tw@gmail.com (Appleboy)</author><guid>https://blog.wu-boy.com/2026/02/why-we-migrated-from-bitbucket-dc-to-gitea-en/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.wu-boy.com/images/2026-02-16/blog-cover_800x447.png" alt="cover">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the software development field, most people are no strangers to &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/">Git&lt;/a>—the world’s most popular version control system and a foundational tool for modern collaborative development. And when we talk about Git, we can’t help but think of &lt;a href="https://github.com/">GitHub&lt;/a>, the largest and most well-known open-source software platform today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, for many private companies or small to mid-sized teams, GitHub may not be an option due to security, cost, deployment strategies, or regulatory requirements. In such cases, what tools can serve as an internal Git repository platform? The most common choices include &lt;a href="https://about.gitlab.com/">GitLab&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://about.gitea.com/">Gitea&lt;/a>, which is the focus of this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some teams, Gitea might still be relatively unfamiliar. Simply put, &lt;strong>Gitea is a lightweight, self-hosted Git platform written in Go&lt;/strong>, providing GitHub-like capabilities such as code hosting, permission management, Issues and Pull Requests, and CI/CD. You can find a more comprehensive explanation in the official documentation (&lt;a href="https://docs.gitea.com/">Gitea Documentation&lt;/a>). It’s cross-platform, easy to deploy, and low-maintenance, which is why it has been increasingly favored by small and medium-sized teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main purpose of this article is to share why our team ultimately decided to migrate from &lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/enterprise/data-center/bitbucket">Bitbucket Data Center&lt;/a> to Gitea—and why we didn’t choose a more feature-rich but comparatively heavier open-source solution like GitLab.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>為什麼團隊從 Bitbucket Data Center 版本轉向 Gitea 企業版</title><link>https://blog.wu-boy.com/2026/02/why-we-migrated-from-bitbucket-dc-to-gitea-zh-tw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:33:55 +0800</pubDate><author>appleboy.tw@gmail.com (Appleboy)</author><guid>https://blog.wu-boy.com/2026/02/why-we-migrated-from-bitbucket-dc-to-gitea-zh-tw/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.wu-boy.com/images/2026-02-16/blog-cover_800x447.png" alt="cover">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>相信在軟體開發領域，大家對 &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/">Git&lt;/a> 應該都不陌生——這套全球最受歡迎的版本控制系統已成為現代協作開發的基礎工具。而提到 Git，就不得不想到目前全球最大且最知名的開源軟體平台 &lt;a href="https://github.com/">GitHub&lt;/a>。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>但在許多私人企業或中小型團隊中，如果因為安全性、成本、部署策略或法規需求等原因，而不能直接採用 GitHub，那麼有哪些工具可以作為企業內部的 Git 版本庫平台呢？最常見的選擇包含 &lt;a href="https://about.gitlab.com/">GitLab&lt;/a> 以及本篇將深入探討的 &lt;a href="https://about.gitea.com/">Gitea&lt;/a>。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>對部分團隊而言，Gitea 可能還相對陌生。簡單來說，&lt;strong>Gitea 是一套以 Go 語言打造的極輕量、自架型 Git 平台&lt;/strong>，提供與 GitHub 類似的功能，例如程式碼託管、權限管理、Issue 與 Pull Request、CI/CD 等能力。 你也可以在官方文件中看到更完整說明（&lt;a href="https://docs.gitea.com/">Gitea Documentation&lt;/a>）。它跨平台、容易部署，且維護成本低，因此逐漸受到中小型團隊青睞。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>本篇文章的主軸，就是要和大家分享： 為什麼我們團隊最終選擇從 &lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/enterprise/data-center/bitbucket">Bitbucket Data Center&lt;/a> 遷移到 Gitea？又為什麼沒有選擇 GitLab 這類功能更完整、但相對較為沉重的開源方案？&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>